# **Jayshri Rathod**

M: +91-9322735902 E: jayur0755@gmail.com A: Pune Maharashtra-

411046

## **Objective:**

Desire to work professional, IT experience and having strong knowledge of **software design**, **development**, **implementation the web-based application** using **Django** with **Python** Technologies. A supportive and flexible team player with a proven entrepreneurial approach towards business goals and objectives. I have been working as a Python Developer for **3.2+** years.

# **Technical Proficiency:**

Programming Languages : Python (3.X)Web Framework : Django (2.X)

Web service : Django REST Framework (DRF)
 Web Technologies : JSON, YAML, Batch Files (.bat)

ORM Framework : Django DBPython libraries : Numpy, Pandas

Development Tools : Visual Studio Code, PyCharmWeb Designing : HTML, CSS, Django Templates

Development IDE : PyCharm, Atom, Vscode, Visual Studio-2019, Swagger Editing Tool(swagger.io).

Web server : WSGI, NGINX

Database Skills : MySQL, SQLite3, SQL Server, Oracle Client.

Database Connectors : PyMySQL, MySQL client.API Testing Tools : Postman, Swagger

Versioning Tools : Git, GitHub, Bitbucket, SourceTree.

Project Management Tool : eJIRA
 Basic Knowledge : SSIS, ETL
 Logging Framework : Logger
 Cloud Technologies : Heroku
 Project Methodologies : Agile - Scrum

#### **Experience Biography:**

- Having 3.2+ Years of IT experience having strong knowledge of software design, development, implementation of web-based application using Django Framework with Python Technologies.
- Very Strong Understanding of all phases in Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC).
- Expertise in Software life cycle of Python Application Developments, including Analysis, Requirements
  Gathering, Design, Development, Implementation, Maintenance and Enhancements.
- Well conversant with REST API and Web application development using Django Web Framework.
- Good working experience with Python, Django, SQL, JSON, logging framework, SQLAlchemy, YAML, ETL, SSIS,
  Pandas, Postman, Swagger.
- Hands on experience with databases such as MySQL, SQLite3, SQL Server, Oracle Client.
- Expertise in **OOP's Object-Oriented Programming** in Python.
- Knowledge of Versioning tools like GIT, GitHub, Bitbucket, SourceTree.
- Good Knowledge on project tracking management tool like **JIRA**.
- Good Experience in working on Projects in Agile-Scrum Environment.
- Hands on experience in application development using IDEs like VS Code, Pycharm.

**Python Developer** 

## **Employment History:**

Organization: MyClan Services Pvt. Ltd., Pune, Maharashtra.

| Python Developer | Nov 2023 - Till Date.

Organization: Rosemallow Technologies Pvt. Ltd., Coimbatore, Tamil Nadu

|Software Engineer| July 2022 - Oct 2023.

**Organization:** Payas Systems Pvt. Ltd, Pune – Maharashtra.

| Software Engineer | Jun 2021 - July 2022.

## **Work Experience:**

# Project 3: "DNC\_Portal"

**Platform Environment:** Python, Django, Django rest framework, MySQL, SSMS, Oracle Client, GIT, GitHub, ORM, JSON.

**Description:** DNC\_Portal is a centralized system to manage Projects, tasks, Finance (Bar for projects), MoM, Deployments and graphical representation of projects, bars, MoM, tasks, timesheets and IT support. The portal is developed for client where we integrate different modules in this portal. Access given for clients which helped them to analyze the ongoing, completed and pipeline projects and respective bars and other important workflow and status in better and easier way in form of charts, bar graphs and other form of data.

## **Roles and Responsibilities:**

- Worked on Backend Modules.
- > I am the responsible for handling the day to issues and fine tuning the application for enhanced the performance.
- > I am actively involved in developing the methods /functions for CRUD in active record.
- I am working on backend part of the application using Django to create API's and maintain the database.
- ➤ Involving in developing various Rest API's as per requirement.
- ➤ Code integration with Git, GitHub.
- Resolve technical issue by debugging, support coding and testing function.
- Checking the developed module by running Unittest whenever necessary.
- Use postman for API testing.

# Project 2: "Client Banking Account Management"

**Platform Environment:** Python, Django, Django rest framework, SSMS, Oracle Client, Bitbucket, SourceTree, Raw SQL, JSON, YAML.

**Description:** Client Banking Account management is a centralized system to manage end user's banking account details with the bank (client). The management details included the end user's account details like account information, application status, account rejection details, user address details, account balance details etc. This included the highly encrypted credentials from the request as the data was related to the banking domain, also the data was limited to only the Read access for the security purpose. The main purpose of the backend was to provide the user details associated with the client account with the client bank.

## **Roles and Responsibilities:**

- Work on bug fixing and improving application performance.
- > Integration of user-oriented elements into different applications, data storage solutions.
- Database maintenance.
- Provide technical assistance for designing and maintenance.
- Code integration with Bitbucket and SourceTree.
- Resolve technical issue by debugging, support coding and testing function.
- > Checking the developed module by running Unittest whenever necessary.

## Project 1: "DealInTrade POS"

Platform Environment: Python, Django, Django rest framework, MySQL, GIT, GitHub, ORM, JSON.

**Description:** DealInTrade POS is one of the best billing & invoicing software. It manages your billing, inventory, accounts, CRM, barcode stickers, and sales reports to boost your businesses. It is an all inclusive POS software solution that takes care of all your business needs. DealInTrade POS makes store management easier. It is a very efficient POS system software in addition to that, it provides extra features to boost your sales. It takes care of financial accounting, taxation, sales, and purchases, among many others.

# **Roles and Responsibilities:**

- Worked on Backend Module.
- > Integrated web service such as REST into database management project using Python implement.
- Responsible for creating various API's.
- Working with some ORM (Object Relational Mapper) libraries.
- Management of stock of inventory products of multiple branches efficiently.
- Good exposure over Core Python and Object Oriented Programming.
- Code integration with GIT.
- Resolve technical issue by debugging, support coding and testing function.
- Work on bug fixing and improving application performance.
- Use postman for API testing.

Master of Science from Amaravati University, Maharashtra.	
Declarations:	
I, hereby declare that all the above information is true and to the best of my knowledge. I am also in possession of all required documents that will be provided at the time of verification.	

Miss. (Jayshri D. Rathod)

**Education:** 

Date: